artik.cloud 2019-06-07

# Privacy Policy — Samsung ARTIK Cloud

**Last Updated: May 25, 2018**

## SAMSUNG ARTIK CLOUD™ PLATFORM PRIVACY POLICY HIGHLIGHTS

### Your Information. Your Rights. Our Responsibilities.

Samsung is committed to maintaining the privacy and security of your Personal Information, and we appreciate that medical information is particularly sensitive. This Privacy Policy applies to the SAMSUNG ARTIK CLOUD™ Platform (the "Platform"), the ARTIK CLOUD websites ([https://artik.cloud](https://artik.cloud/), [https://developer.artik.cloud](https://developer.artik.cloud/), [https://trials.artik.cloud](https://trials.artik.cloud/), and [https://trials-admin.artik.cloud](https://trials-admin.artik.cloud/)), and any related Samsung device, website or online application that refers or links to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the "Platform"). This Privacy Policy does not address personal information that you provide to us in other contexts (e.g., through a business relationship not related to the Platform). 

**For European Economic Area, Switzerland and the UK, please see Samsung’s Data Privacy Notice, available[here](https://artik.cloud/privacy.html#european).**

Any personal information that you provide when you use the Platform belongs to you and, in accordance with this Privacy Policy, we want you to understand how it may be collected, used and shared. 

### Information We Collect

We collect various types of information in connection with the Platform, including: 

  * Account information you provide to us when you open your ARTIK CLOUD™ account, such as your name and email address;
  * Information you provide directly to us when you register to use a Samsung Website or obtain an application or service provided by the Platform or other Samsung Products, such as your email address, user name or information about your product preferences;
  * Information we collect about your use of the Services, such as which products you use and information about your usage patterns; and
  * Information from a device or mobile application connected to the Platform, including technical information such as your IP address and other unique online identifiers.

We may also seek your consent to collection of information not described in the Privacy Policy. 

### Use and Sharing of Information

We use the information we collect to, among other things: 

  * Provide the Platform and other Services; and
  * Understand the way you use the services so that we can improve your experience.

We also use the information we collect in ways described to you at the point of collection, or otherwise with your consent. 

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, we will not share your information with third parties. We allow the device makers or the mobile application providers to access your personal information where you have provided consent to allow us to do this, and you may revoke your consent to such access at any time. We may also share your information with: 

  * Service providers – companies that provide services for or on behalf of Samsung; and
  * Law enforcement or regulators – when we are required to do so or to protect Samsung and our users.

### How To Contact Us

Log into the Samsung ARTIK Platform here: [https://my.artik.cloud](https://my.artik.cloud/)

Send an email to our Data Protection Officer at: [dataprotection@samsung.com](mailto:dataprotection@samsung.com)

Send a written request to:

Data Protection Office  
Samsung Electronics Europe Samsung House   
1000 Hillswood Drive   
Chertsey, Surrey KT16 0PS United Kingdom 

## SAMSUNG ARTIK CLOUD™ PLATFORM PRIVACY POLICY

Samsung Semiconductor, Inc., together with any subsidiaries and/or affiliates that license materials for the SAMSUNG ARTIK CLOUD ™ Platform ("Samsung," "we," "us," "our") know how important privacy is to our customers, and we strive to be clear about how we collect, use, disclose, transfer and store your information. This privacy policy (the "Privacy Policy") provides an overview of our information practices. The Privacy Policy applies to (i) the SAMSUNG ARTIK CLOUD™ Platform, a platform operated by Samsung that enables mobile devices and applications to upload information, (ii) the following SAMSUNG ARTIK CLOUD™ websites: [https://artik.cloud](https://artik.cloud/) (the "User Portal"), [https://developer.artik.cloud](https://developer.artik.cloud/) (the "Developer Portal"), [https://trials-admin.artik.cloud](https://trials-admin.artik.cloud/) (the "Trial Tool Administrator Site") and [https://trials.artik.cloud](https://trials.artik.cloud/) (the "Trial Tool Participant Site"), and (iii) any Samsung device, website or online application that links to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the "Platform"). This Privacy Policy does not address personal information that you provide to us in other contexts (e.g., through a business relationship not related to the Platform). All capitalized terms shall have the same definitions as provided under the Platform Terms and Developer License Agreement, unless otherwise defined herein. 

Please note that this Privacy Policy applies regardless of whether you use a computer, mobile phone, tablet, TV, or other device to access the Platform. It is important that you read the Privacy Policy carefully because anytime you use the Platform, you consent to the practices we describe in the Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the practices described in the Privacy Policy, you should not use the Platform or click on the "I Agree" button (if available). 

### WHAT THIS PRIVACY POLICY COVERS

This Privacy Policy covers how Samsung treats personally identifiable information that it collects and receives through the Platform. "Personal Information" means information about you that is personally identifiable or from which you can be identified together with other information (e.g., your name, address, email address or phone number). 

### WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU?

We do not collect Personal Information about you through the Platform without your knowledge or action. We use Personal Information that we collect to (i) provide the Platform services you request; (ii) understand the way you use the Platform services so that we can improve your experience; (iii) comply with our legal and regulatory obligations and our legitimate business interests; and (iv) offer you products or services we consider may be of interest to you or for other marketing purposes. Your information is collected and used in the following ways through the Platform. 

**The Platform**. Samsung operates the Platform, which offers an interface that allows cloud-based services to store and exchange data from diverse devices. The Platform exposes application programming interfaces (APIs) that enable developers to store or read data from devices, services and mobile applications. The Personal Information collected through the APIs and hosted on the Platform's cloud servers may include, but is not limited to, name, credit card information, and other demographic information of the user and biometric health data recorded by the third party service, or a device. The Personal Information collected through the Platform is used to offer the Platform's services. Personal Information stored through the Platform may include medical information if a user has chosen to store such information. The Personal Information is transferred to the United States and South Korea (where privacy laws may not be as adequate as in the jurisdiction in which you are based if outside the United States or South Korea) to Samsung and third parties engaged by Samsung to enable us to operate the Platform or provide a service to you. By using the Platform you expressly agree to the transfer of the Personal Information to the United States and South Korea. 

**Platform Websites**. Samsung offers various products and services on websites associated with the Platform, including the User Portal, the Developer Portal, the Trial Tool Administrator Site and the Trial Tool Site. Personal Information is collected through the registration forms of the Platform websites, and may include, but is not limited to, name, phone number, fax number, email address and, if applicable, credit card information. The Personal Information collected through the Platform websites is used to offer the particular products and services available through the Platform. 

**Information About Your Use of the Platform**. In addition to the information you provide, we may collect information about your use of the Platform, such as the applications and devices you use, the websites you visit, and how you interact with content offered through a Platform service. 

**Other Information We Collect**. We also may collect other information about you, your device(s), or your use of the Platform in ways that we describe to you at the point of collection or otherwise with your consent. 

**Protected Health Information Subject to HIPAA**. When Samsung provides the Platform to certain healthcare providers, health plans and other healthcare organizations, Samsung may be subject to federal healthcare privacy and security standards under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act ("HIPAA") or equivalent provisions protecting sensitive personal data under other applicable laws. To the extent that the Personal Information provided to Samsung is "protected health information" subject to HIPAA or sensitive personal data subject to equivalent provisions in other applicable laws, Samsung will safeguard the privacy and security of that information in accordance with applicable HIPAA or other applicable legal requirements. 

### TO WHOM DO WE DISCLOSE YOUR INFORMATION?

Except as described below and in this Privacy Policy, we will not disclose your Personal Information to any third parties without your consent. 

Disclosures to Certain Third Parties. We may disclose your Personal Information to our subcontractors, agents, or payment service providers (who may be located in the United States) that we contract with to assist us in providing the Platform; provided that any such subcontractors or agents shall agree in writing to comply with the privacy and security standards described in this Privacy Policy. 

Disclosures Under Special Circumstances. There may be instances when we disclose your Personal Information to other parties: 

  * to comply with the law or respond to compulsory legal process (such as a search warrant or court order) or request for information from a regulator;
  * to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing the Platform; or
  * to protect the rights, property or safety of Samsung, or any of our respective affiliates, business partners, or customers.

Other Parties in Connection With Corporate Transactions. We may share your Personal Information with other business entities in connection with the sale, assignment, merger or other transfer of all or a portion of Samsung's business to that business entity. We will require any such successor business entity to honor the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

Other Parties With Your Consent or At Your Direction. In addition to the disclosures described in this Privacy Policy, we may share information about you with third parties when you consent to or request such sharing. 

### AUTOMATICALLY COLLECTED INFORMATION AND ANONYMOUS INFORMATION

**Aggregated Data**. Samsung collects aggregate queries for internal reporting and also counts, tracks, and aggregates the visitor's activity into Samsung's analysis of general traffic-flow through the Platform. To these ends, Samsung may merge information about you into aggregated group data. In some cases, Samsung may remove personal identifiers from Personal Information and maintain it in aggregate form that may later be combined with other information to generate anonymous, aggregated statistical information. Such anonymous, group data may be shared on an aggregated basis with Samsung's affiliates, business partners, service providers and/or vendors; if it does so, Samsung will not disclose your individual identity. 

**Web Server Logs and IP Addresses**. An Internet Protocol ("IP") address is a number that automatically identifies the computer/machine you have used to access the Internet. The IP address enables our server to send you the web pages that you want to visit, and it may disclose the server owned by your Internet Service Provider. Samsung may use IP addresses to conduct website analyses and performance reviews and to administer the Platform. 

**Cookies, Beacons and Similar Technologies**. We, as well as certain third parties that provide content, advertising, or other functionality on our services, may use cookies, beacons, and other technologies in certain areas of our services. 

**Cookies**. Cookies are small files that store information on your computer, mobile phone or other device. They enable the entity that put the cookie on your device to recognize you across different websites, services, devices, and/or browsing sessions. Cookies serve many useful purposes. For example: 

  * Cookies can remember your sign-in credentials so you don't have to enter those credentials each time you log on to a service.
  * Cookies help us and third parties understand which parts of our services are the most popular because they help us to see which pages and features visitors are accessing and how much time they are spending on the pages. By studying this kind of information, we are better able to adapt the services and provide you with a better experience.
  * Cookies help us provide you with relevant content by collecting information about your use of the Platform and other websites and apps.

When you use a web browser to access a website, you can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is sent. Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences. The operating system of your device may contain additional controls for cookies. For further information about cookies see www.allaboutcookies.org.

Please note, however, that some services may be designed to work using cookies and that disabling cookies may affect your ability to use those services, or certain parts of them. 

**Other Local Storage**. We, along with certain third parties, may use other kinds of local storage technologies, such as Local Shared Objects (also referred to as "Flash cookies") and HTML5 local storage, in connection with our services. These technologies are similar to the cookies discussed above in that they are stored on your device and can be used to store certain information about your activities and preferences. However, these technologies may make use of different parts of your device from standard cookies, and so you might not be able to control them using standard browser tools and settings. For information about disabling or deleting information contained in Flash cookies, please click here: <http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html>. 

**Beacons**. We also may use technologies called beacons (or "pixels") that communicate information from your device to a server. Beacons can be embedded in online content, videos, and emails, and can allow a server to read certain types of information from your device, know when you have viewed particular content or a particular email message, determine the time and date on which you viewed the beacon, and the IP address of your device. We may use beacons for a variety of purposes, including to analyze the use of the Platform and (in conjunction with cookies) to provide content that is more relevant to you. 

**_By accessing and using the Platform or our website, you expressly consent to the storage of cookies, other local storage technologies, beacons and other information on your devices. You also consent to the access of such cookies, local storage technologies, beacons and information by us._**

### SECURITY

Samsung understands that storing data in a secure manner is essential. Samsung stores Personal Information and other data using reasonable physical, technical and administrative safeguards to secure data against foreseeable risks, such as unauthorized use, access, disclosure, destruction or modification. Although we make good faith efforts to store the information we collect in a secure operating environment that is not available to the public, we cannot guarantee complete security. Further, while we work to ensure the integrity and security of our network and systems, we cannot guarantee that our security measures will prevent third-party "hackers" from illegally obtaining this information. 

### LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES

Our Platform services may link to third-party websites and services that are outside our control. We are not responsible for the security or privacy of any information collected by such websites or other services. You should exercise caution, and review the privacy statements applicable to the third-party websites and services you use. We also make available to you certain products or services (e.g., apps available through the Platform) developed by third parties. Samsung is not responsible for these third-party products or services. 

### CHILDREN'S PRIVACY PROTECTION

Under Age 13

We do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of thirteen (13) without parental consent, unless permitted by law. If we learn that a child under the age of thirteen (13) has provided us with personal information, we will delete it in accordance with applicable law. 

Under Age 18

Minors under 18 years of age may have the Personal Information that they have provided to Samsung while using the Platform deleted by sending an email to [privacy@artik.cloud](mailto:privacy@artik.cloud) requesting deletion. Please note that, while we make reasonable efforts to comply with such requests, deletion of your personal information does not ensure complete and comprehensive removal of that data from all systems. 

### DO NOT TRACK SIGNALS AND SIMILAR MECHANISMS

Some web browsers may transmit "do-not-track" signals to the websites with which the user communicates, although web browsers incorporate and activate this functionality in different ways, and it is not always clear whether users intend for these signals to be transmitted. There currently is disagreement, including among participants in the leading Internet standards-setting organization, concerning what, if anything, websites should do when they receive such signals. Samsung currently does not take action in response to these signals, but, if and when a standard is established and accepted, we may reassess how to respond to these signals. 

### CORRECTING, UPDATING OR DELETING INFORMATION

The Platform gives users the option to correct, update or delete information previously provided to us by the user; however, we will maintain copies of user information to the extent retained as part of the Platform's standard backup/archive process or required by law or regulatory requirements and subject to our legal obligations. 

To make changes to your contact information, or to opt out of receiving information, please contact us in one of the following ways: 

Log into the Samsung ARTIK Platform here: [https://my.artik.cloud](https://my.artik.cloud/)

Send an email to our Data Protection Officer at: [dataprotection@samsung.com](mailto:dataprotection@samsung.com)

Send a written request to:

Data Protection Office  
Samsung Electronics Europe Samsung House   
1000 Hillswood Drive   
Chertsey, Surrey KT16 0PS United Kingdom 

### POLICY UPDATES

It is important that you check back often for updates to the Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy may be revised from time to time as we add new features and services, as laws change, and as industry privacy and security best practices evolve. If we update the Privacy Policy, we will let you know about our changes we consider material by placing a note on the relevant web page you use to access the Platform services. By accessing or using the Platform after we have placed such a notice, you consent to the new practice(s) identified in the update. The most current version of the Privacy Policy will always be available on <https://artik.cloud/privacy.html>. You can check the "effective date" posted at the top to see when the Privacy Policy was last updated. If we make any change to this Privacy Policy regarding use or disclosure of Personal Information, we will provide advance notice on the web page you use to access the Platform services. Small changes or changes that do not significantly affect individual privacy interests may be made at any time and without prior notice. 

### QUESTIONS?

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or about Samsung's handling of your information, please contact [dataprotection@samsung.com](mailto:dataprotection@samsung.com).

## European Residents: Data Privacy Notice

**Last Updated: May 25, 2018**

**Your Information. Your Rights. Our Responsibilities.**

The SAMSUNG ARTIK CLOUD™ platform (the “Platform”) collects and processes your personal information that is provided by you, as the End User, or generated by you in your use of the Platform, the ARTIK CLOUD™ website and your use of the mobile applications and related services (collectively the “Services”). This Privacy Notice is provided to you in accordance with applicable privacy laws including, but not limited to, laws implementing the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (GDPR) (the “ **Data Privacy Laws** ”). It applies only to residents in the European Economic Area ("EEA"), Switzerland and the UK who use the Platform and it explains what information you provide to us (through connecting your apps to the Platform and your account) and how we use your information to provide the Services to you and manage your account. This Privacy Notice is not applicable to End Users in any other territory other than in the EEA, Switzerland and the UK. All capitalized terms shall have the same definitions as provided under the Samsung ARTIK Cloud Terms of Service, unless otherwise defined herein. 

We, Samsung Semiconductor, Inc., together with any subsidiaries and/or affiliates that license materials for the SAMSUNG ARTIK CLOUD ™ Platform (collectively, " **Samsung** ", " **we** ", " **us** " or " **our** ") offer the Services to Users both through the Platform directly and through various Integrated Services offered by Third Parties you may choose to use via your ARTIK Cloud Account, and so you may modify and change your privacy settings through such Integrated Services (as applicable). Any Integrated Service or other Third Party Product that you use in connection with the Services must inform you of how your personal information is used and shared when you use or connect to that Third Party Product and you have privacy rights against such entities in this regard. 

We include in this Privacy Notice a summary of your rights to control how we use your personal information. We aim to put you, the end user, in control of how your personal information is used by Samsung as we provide the Services. We are a data controller under the Data Privacy Laws in relation to your Samsung account holder information and other information as described in the “Your personal information” section below. We may also, in some limited respects, act as a data controller of your personal data stored in the Platform where you have directly connected your ARTIK Cloud account with a Third Party Product, but this capacity is limited to the means of storing the personal data rather than the use of the personal data, which remains controlled by the Third Party Product. In all other aspects, Samsung acts as a data processor for the Third Party Products to which you connect or use with your ARTIK CLOUD account. 

This Privacy Notice should be read with our [Privacy Policy](https://artik.cloud/privacy.html) which deals with the Platform, both of which are updated from time to time.

**Your personal information**

Your personal information includes any information relating to you where you are identified or from which you are identifiable. This includes your name, photos, videos, information about where you live and your use of devices and mobile applications. If you share information about other individuals, such as family and friends, you expressly warrant and undertake that you have their permission to do so in compliance with the Data Privacy Laws. 

We collect various types of personal information in connection with the Platform from different sources, including: 

  * Account information you provide to us when you open your ARTIK CLOUD™ account, such as your name and email address;
  * Information you provide directly to us when you register to use a Samsung Website or obtain an application or service provided by the Platform or other Samsung Products, such as your email address, user name or information about your product preferences;
  * Information we collect about your use of the Services, such as which products you use and information about your usage patterns; 
  * Information from a device or mobile application connected to the Platform, including technical information such as your IP address and other unique online identifiers; and

Some of the personal information you provide to us, if you consent, may include health information or other sensitive or special categories of personal information. Typically, we do not access your personal information from your apps and connected devices unless there is a request from you for technical assistance. In this event, in restricted circumstances, our technical team may have access to your personal data uploaded or accessed by these apps and devices. More usually, we only have access to the information provided to open your ARTIK CLOUD™ account. The mobile applications and devices you use in connection with the Services, however, have access to your personal information in the Platform, which is determined by your use of these mobile applications and devices and your privacy settings. 

**What we do with your personal information**

All the personal information we collect from you or generated by you is used to provide the Platform and other Services. Samsung does not typically access your personal information other to facilitate the provision of the Services to you and to operate, evaluate and improve our products and services. We process personal information for these purposes because we have a legitimate interest in administering and providing the Services to you. You have the ability to set and modify the privacy settings in the apps and devices you connect to your ARTIK Cloud Account. We allow the device makers or the mobile application providers to access your personal information where you have provided consent to allow us to do this, and you may revoke your consent to such access at any time.

You may also consent to us using your personal information for additional purposes not described in the Privacy Policy but which we consider may be of interest to you from time to time. We will not use your personal information for these additional purposes without your consent. You have the right to tell us that you do not want to be contacted by us for these additional purposes any time after you initially provide your consent. We also use your information to send you electronic direct marketing and promotional messages where you have consented to receive marketing communications from us. 

We also process your personal information to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations and/or our contractual obligations to you to provide the Services, to manage your account with us and to manage technical issues that may arise. 

Your personal information is processed by us in the United States and is held on servers provided by AWS in the United States and Korea, which may have a lower standard of data privacy laws than your country of residence. Our security measures are described below in this Privacy Notice. AWS has assured us that it has security measures which are compliant with applicable Data Privacy Laws (see <https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/security/aws-and-the-general-data-protection-regulation/>). Samsung affiliates providing Services will also enter into European Commission-approved Standard Contractual Clauses where required for data transfers from the EEA, Switzerland and the UK. For more information about our security measures, these Clauses or to receive a copy of them, use the contact information below.

We may share your personal information with other companies in the Samsung group for the purposes described in this Privacy Notice. Unless you have authorized us to do so through your use of an Integrated Service or other Third Party Product, we do not allow any third parties to have access to your personal information, except as required or permitted by applicable laws or in accordance with the Privacy Policy and Terms of Service. We may disclose your personal information to our subcontractors, agents, or payment service providers (who may be located in the United States) that we contract with to assist us in providing the Services, who are required to use or disclose personal information only as necessary to perform services on our behalf or comply with applicable legal requirements.

There may be instances when we disclose your personal information to other parties: 

  * if we are required or permitted to do so by law or legal process (such as a search warrant or court order) or request for information from a regulator or otherwise for legal purposes;
  * to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing the Services; 
  * when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent harm or financial loss; or
  * to protect the rights, property or safety of Samsung, or any of our respective affiliates, business partners, or customers or otherwise in the legitimate business interests of Samsung and/or our affiliates and in accordance with Data Privacy Laws.

We may share your personal information with other business entities in connection with the sale, assignment, merger or other transfer of all or a portion of Samsung's business or assets to that business entity.

**How we protect your personal information**

Samsung understands that storing data in a secure manner is essential. Samsung stores personal information and other data using reasonable physical, technical and administrative safeguards to secure data against foreseeable risks, such as unauthorized use, access, disclosure, destruction or modification. Although we make good faith efforts to store the information we collect in a secure operating environment that is not available to the public, we cannot guarantee complete security. Further, while we work to ensure the integrity and security of our network and systems, we cannot guarantee that our security measures will prevent third-party "hackers" from illegally obtaining this information. 

**How long we keep it**

As a general matter, personal information relating to your use of Services is deleted approximately thirty days after it first becomes available on the Platform unless an integrated service with which you are using the Services has purchased an additional data retention service from us. We retain personal information relating to your account for the period for which we provide the Services to you and for a further period of seven to ten years after the ARTIK CLOUD™ account is closed for legal, regulatory, audit and tax requirements. Any personal information which you have provided to us for marketing purposes will be kept until you notify us that you no longer wish to receive this information. We aim to maintain our services in a manner that protects information from accidental or malicious destruction. Because of this, after information is deleted from our services, we may not immediately delete residual copies from our active servers and may not remove information from our backup systems.

**Notification of other Samsung services and products**

We would like to use your name and email address to inform you of our future or related services, offers and similar products. If you provide us with your consent to receive marketing communications, we will offer the right to unsubscribe in each electronic communication. This information is not shared with third parties and you can unsubscribe at any time via email, the Platform or through our website. 

**What are your rights?**

You have the right to ensure your personal information is accurate. To make changes to your contact and other account information, or to opt out of receiving marketing communications, please contact us in one of the following ways: 

Log into the Samsung ARTIK Platform here: [https://my.artik.cloud](https://my.artik.cloud/)

Send an email to our Data Protection Officer at: [dataprotection@samsung.com](mailto:dataprotection@samsung.com)

Send a written request to:

Data Protection Office  
Samsung Electronics Europe Samsung House   
1000 Hillswood Drive   
Chertsey, Surrey KT16 0PS United Kingdom 

You have the right to request that we delete your personal information. In this event, we will close your account and retain your personal information as described above in this Privacy Notice. You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information or object to the processing of your personal information on grounds relating to your particular situation. This may compromise your ability to use the Services. 

You also have the right to transfer your account details to another cloud provider. We will, following your written request to us, provide you with your relevant personal information in a machine-readable format to transfer to another cloud provider. 

If you wish to raise a complaint on how we have handled your personal information, you can contact our Data Protection Officer (details above) who will investigate the matter and respond to you promptly.

If you are not satisfied with our response, you can complain to any applicable data privacy authority in your country of residence. 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice or about Samsung’s handling of your information, please contact [dataprotection@samsung.com](mailto:dataprotection@samsung.com).
